back from the fitcher
even marty mcfly and doc brown could not
have predicted for the fitness world to
reach this point smart gems are arguably
the hottest piece of equipment right now
and i've got another one loaded up for
you guys today the fitcher smart gym
i've been using mine for a couple weeks
so now i'm gonna share my findings with
you guys in today's review
what's up everybody it's jake back once
again in the barbing garage gym and in
for review today i've got the fitcher
smart gym in this video i'm going to
tell you everything you need to know
about this high-tech piece of equipment
from the price the many features it has
to offer some pros and cons and of
course who should or maybe should not
purchase this smart gym but before i get
started i have to let you know we've
reviewed a lot of smart gyms on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just search barbind best smart
gyms and you can find out which ones we
like the best but also which ones might
suit you the best
[Music]
okay so there's a lot to like about
fitcher but why don't we start with the
obvious it has a sleek design it takes
up minimal space in your home kind of
like a full-length mirror really would
there's a companion app you can download
and this is where you're going to be
able to pick and choose from the
hundreds of classes that are available
through fisher as well as track your
activity over time
there's a lot of workout programs for
you to choose from but you can even make
your own personal workout program you
can mix up the difficulty and the
intensity of your workouts as well as
get elements of hit strength training
and even dance cardio once you're done
with the class simply wave at the screen
and it's going to immediately jump into
that next workout for you but when
you're looking for a class you can
filter your results based off the
equipment type you're using such as
dumbbells or resistance bands what part
of the body you want to focus on the
length of the class and even which
instructor you want to lead that class
there's new classes that get dropped
weekly and there's even a challenges tab
where this is going to put you on a
global leader board pitting you head to
head against the rest of the fitcher
community so this challenges tab it's
going to give you 60 seconds to perform
as many reps of a particular exercise as
you can such as squats so the more you
do the higher your rank on that
leaderboard and thanks to a camera
that's built into the feature you're
going to get your form corrected in real
time whenever needed as well as counting
your reps for each individual class but
don't worry fitcher does include a lens
cover if you ever want to cover that
camera for whatever reason
[Music]
okay so there are a few potential issues
that you might run into with the fixture
let's start with the obvious again it's
not cheap listed right around fifteen
hundred dollars on the fitcher website
if you want that accessories package
that's gonna come with a heart rate
monitor some resistance bands a water
bottle and some face masks for when
you're out in public the good news is
though you can finance your purchase
through a firm you'll be making monthly
payments of around 40 or so but on top
of that you're also gonna have to pay
for a monthly subscription just to gain
access to the available classes that's
going to be an additional 40 or so so
this might be more ideal if you do have
another person maybe even two or three
that's going to be willing to split all
this up with you okay and since you do
in fact need to connect your feature to
your wi-fi you obviously want to make
sure that you have good connection now
we're in a garage away from the house
and we didn't have much of an issue but
that could be different for you because
you never really know with wi-fi another
thing here is that if you're somebody
who's wanting to really focus on
strength training this might not be the
ideal solution for you with that being
said you're still gonna get a solid
workout in trust me you're gonna feel
the burn
but i didn't really find that strength
training was the main focus with this
piece of equipment
okay so let's talk about pricing now
with the fitcher it's pretty
straightforward as i mentioned you're
gonna be spending right around fifteen
hundred dollars for the device itself
about 150
for that accessories package and right
around 40 a month
for the membership fee just to gain
access to the classes but once again you
do have the luxury of financing your
purchase and making monthly payments of
around 40
through a firm but when you compare it
to a gym membership as well as personal
training classes it might actually be
saving money in the long run if you're
somebody who doesn't lift a ton of heavy
weight and you want to burn some
calories in the comfort of your own home
this is a pretty good option for you to
consider and a really cool thing about
the fit your website is they're actually
going to help you calculate how much
money you're going to be spending per
class based on how many classes you plan
on participating in per week as well as
how many people are on your membership
plan if you're all by yourself on your
membership and you want to work out four
times a week you're gonna be spending
around two dollars and forty cents per
class now if you had one additional
person on your membership and you both
wanna work out four times a week
it's gonna be about 60 cents per class
and if you had that max number of six
additional people on your membership
you're literally gonna be paying pennies
for each class
[Music]
okay so something i love about fitcher
is that there's over a hundred different
classes for you to join in on demand
fashion but i was a little bit surprised
to find that there's no live classes for
you to join but don't let that bring you
down you can still easily spend the day
in a boxing class maybe doing some yoga
some cardio or even just stretching if
you want there's a trending tab which as
you may assume it's going to show you
the most popular classes at any given
time
and that challenge tab i talked about
earlier it's going to give you 60
seconds to perform whatever exercise
they give you and it's going to pin you
head-to-head against the rest of the
fitcher community and give you a global
rank based off how well you do there's
also new classes that are going to be
added every couple of days or so so you
can always mix up your workouts
each workout is led by an instructor
it's going to consist of a warm-up
actual workout as well as a cool down
and something a lot of you guys may love
is that the instructor is gonna
guide you step by step on how to perform
each exercise but they're also gonna
bring the energy and for a lack of a
better word pump you up three two one
switch it hey hey hey hey pop pop hey
hey yes hi knees with me you got it you
jack your feet like a jumping jack but
you bring your
okay so when it comes to the build i
wasn't able to get the exact
specifications for y'all but the frame
does seem to be made from steel which is
nice it's gonna add on to that
durability of the fixture but you're
looking at five different colored
options so you're looking at silver
black blue a bluish green and then let's
call it rose gold now there are
specific names for each color so those
are going to be stardust night ocean
oasis and sunlight now since the screen
is in fact made of glass you do run into
the potential of breaking it so i would
definitely recommend putting it
somewhere as safe as possible and it
does come with a wall mount but i would
suggest just keeping it on the stand
like we have here you do need to lean it
up against the wall because it's not
going to stand alone by itself
but you can still easily move it around
your home if you need to for whatever
reason you need to move it in different
room that's made possible when it's on
the stand
it's 68 inches tall when it's on the
stand it's 23 inches wide it has a depth
of about 1.6 inches and it only weighs
60 pounds so you can definitely move it
around your home if you need to
okay so let's talk about some of the
features now with fitcher as i mentioned
there is a companion app for you to
download that's available for both ios
and android phones that's how you're
gonna control everything the feature
does because it's not touch screen
however it does read your hand gestures
so
if you want to go straight to the next
workout just simply raise your hand and
it'll do that for you
fitcher also has bluetooth capabilities
that way you can connect your heart rate
monitor a fitness tracker some
headphones or maybe even a bluetooth
speaker
the screen is 43 inches and it has 1080p
quality it's going to give you crystal
clear picture during your workouts plus
as you spend time with your fixture all
your stats are going to be tracked this
is going to consist of your weekly stats
your monthly stats and even all-time
stats that's going to include the amount
of classes you participated in the
amount of time you spent working out as
well as how many calories that you've
burnt
now clearly this is a high-tech piece of
equipment so let's talk a little bit
more about that technology now i really
like the camera that's featured on the
feature because it's going to give you
live form feedback and help you correct
anything that does need to be corrected
there's going to be prompts that pop up
on the screen and tell you exactly what
you need to do to get that correct form
and while it may look like it fitcher is
not touch screen so make sure you
download that companion app or else you
can't do anything the dual frequency
stereo speakers on the back of the
fixture are going to give you solid
sound while you're working out not only
of your instructor but also of the music
that's playing while you're working out
and thanks to the bluetooth capabilities
you can connect your fitness tracker a
heart rate monitor your headphones or
maybe even a bluetooth speaker okay so
my favorite feature about fitcher is in
fact the activity tab so this is where
all your stats are going to be recorded
as you spend time with your fixture you
can easily see how many calories you've
burned how many classes you've completed
as well as if you're meeting your goal
number of workouts per week now once
again this is where your heart rate
monitor is going to come into play
because you're going to be able to
accurately see how many calories you
burn weekly and monthly on top of each
individual class
[Music]
okay so i'm gonna walk you all around
the feature now well as much as i can
because i am in a corner over here but
i'm gonna show you a little bit more up
close of the details so the frame is in
fact made of some sort of steel once
again i wasn't able to get the exact
specifications but it does seem really
durable now
the screen obviously is glass now you
want to make sure you put it somewhere
safe some more work nothing's going to
bump into it and possibly crack or break
it so
your camera i talked about that's going
to be located right down here towards
the bottom of the fixture and with your
purchase you do get a lens cap it's
magnetic so just simply find the camera
snap it on you're good to go it's not
going to pick up on anything you can
cover it whenever you need to
your speakers are going to be located on
the back of the device you do need a
three-prong outlet so make sure that is
in close proximity
of your feature and
kind of like a smartphone you do have a
power button as well as your volume up
and down buttons on the side of your
feature
okay so who should purchase fitcher well
this really is an ideal purchase for
anybody who wants to get a proper
workout in without leaving the comfort
of their home and if you're new to
working out you're going to love the
fact that each class is led by
instructor and they're going to lead you
step by step on exactly how to perform
each exercise but that's also a good
thing for experienced athletes too
because you can always learn something
new and that's no different here and
since it takes up minimal space in your
home you can put fitcher almost anywhere
i would just recommend having around
eight square feet of space to get a
proper workout in okay so what about the
people who might not wanna have this on
their radar well a fifteen hundred
dollar price tag on top of a forty
dollar monthly membership
might make this fall out of your price
range if you're wanting to focus on
strength training specifically this
probably is not the product for you
because i didn't find that to be the
main focus and if you're wanting live
classes to join well you're simply not
going to get that at this moment with
fitcher
[Music]
well that's about all i have to say
about the fit your home gym y'all we're
truly living in the future and that's
really made evident by pieces of
equipment such as this it's super easy
to use you can track all of your stats
in the companion app and you can join
any given class at any given moment if
you want to plus it has a super small
footprint which makes it compatible for
nearly everyone and you can even split
your membership up with your friends if
you want to
now since this was just released i would
imagine fitcher is going to be rolling
out some more features in the not too
distant future thanks for watching
everybody i hope you learned a little
bit more today about how fitcher can
help you achieve your fitness goals as
always stay tuned for my next review but
in the meantime why don't you head over
to barbin.com and you can read into more
detail about what we discussed here
today just search barbind fitcher home
gym review and that article is going to
pull right up for you now i'm going to
go sweat
i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
everything is gonna be